-可以去吃午饭了吗  -马上好
- Hey, ready for lunch? - Oh, one sec.
那是太空探测车的驱动系统原型吗
Is that the prototype drive system for the high-G rover?
不是啦  伯纳黛特给我买了运动手环
No, Bernadette got me a Fitbit
好追查我每天运动量有多少
so she can track how much I'm exercising.
看她还敢不敢再关心你健康
That'll teach her to care about your health.
我真想看看哪天我早死时  她震惊的表情
I can't wait to see the look on her face when I die young.
你上一次真的去运动是什么时候
When was the last actual exercise you got?
前几天
The other day, when
她硬要给我戴上手环  我落荒而逃时
she tried to put that Fitbit on me and I ran away from her.
最近一份研究指出
According to a recent study,
哪怕你赖着不动  只要心中想着运动
simply thinking about exercise, even while sitting still,
就能给身体带来好处
can have physical benefits.
指不定我现在就在运动呢
For all you know, I could be exercising right now.
-那你是吗  -还是明天再想吧
- Are you? - Eh, I'll do it tomorrow.
我们多运动一点也不是什么坏事啊
It wouldn't be the worst thing if we were more active.
兄台此言甚是有理
Oh. You make an excellent point.
跑步的愉悦感蹭蹭往上飙啊
Ooh, I think I'm getting a runner's high!
当运动量超过某一阶段时  体内便会分泌脑内啡
会有如同吗啡一样的止痛和欣快感
翻译：干将莫邪赛太公  双剑合璧YY猫
猫中之王  别扭大菜
看看大学里的各种运动社团
Look at all these activities the university has.
攀岩社  射箭  夺旗橄榄球
Rock climbing club, archery, flag football.
旗字让我兴奋  橄榄球让我无力
Had me at flag, lost me at football.
我觉得你们想要多动动真的很棒
Yeah, I think it's great you guys want to get more exercise,
可是你们真觉得选择运动合适吗
but do you really think sports is the right choice for you?
你什么意思
What are you saying?
我们身体协调性太差不适合玩体育吗
We're not coordinated enough to play sports?
莱纳德  亲爱的
Okay, Leonard, sweetheart,
你玩个拼字游戏都能扭伤脚踝
you twisted your ankle playing Scrabble.
那一次堪比打麻将  连庄还自摸清一色
I got a triple-word score with a double letter "Q."
此时不跳庆祝嘚瑟舞
If that's not a time to bust out the Scrabble dance,
那这舞还有啥存在价值
what's the point of having one?
巴里·克瑞普吉开了一个击剑俱乐部呢
Hey, Barry Kripke started a fencing club.
有意思
Interesting.
击剑的吸引力在于不失风度
Sword fighting does hold a certain elegant appeal.
同时也满足了我们几个
And I would imagine it meets many
对运动项目的要求
of our personal criteria for a sport.
它在室内进行  不需要擦防晒霜
It's indoors, so no sunscreen.
不需要扔  不需要接
No throwing, no catching,
还不需要跑
no running.
不用穿可能会被人脱的体育短裤
No gym shorts that can be yanked down.
或更惨  被人用力往上提
Or worse, up.
同意
Preach.
而且有个加分项
And as an added bonus,
"一针见血"这词原是击剑中得分之意
the word "touche" comes from fencing.
是我们唯一能不带隐喻地
It would be our only opportunity to use it
使用这词的地方
in a non-metaphorical sense.
玩捉人游戏的法国校园中也能吧
What about a game of tag on a French schoolyard?
你这话"一针见血"
Ah, touche.
多谢你们能来
Thanks for coming by.
没事  需要我们帮忙什么
Sure. So how can we help?
我知道现在越来越多女人买漫画书
Well, I know more women are buying comics than ever,
但不知道为何  我没法把她们吸引进我的店
but for some reason, I-I can't get 'em in here.
目前你试过哪些揽女客的办法呢
All right, well, what have you tried so far?
我试着摆出更多女性导向的漫画
Uh, I've-I've been stocking more female-oriented titles.
洗手间里
Uh, in the bathroom,
我特意把厕纸尾端折成小三角造型
I folded the end of the toilet paper into a triangle.
而且呢
And, uh,
你们现在坐的地方正是特选"哺乳区"
you are now sitting in the official breastfeeding area.
在漫画店里这样好吗
Really? In a comic book store?
不用担心  我在这里正上方装了监控
Oh, don't worry. I-I've got a camera right up here,
这样我就能从收银台监视
so I could watch from the counter
确保没有变态男客偷看
and make sure guys aren't being pervs.
总之  我该怎么样做
Anyway, so what do I got to do to-to
才能揽进女客呢
get you in the door?
首先呢
Well, for starters,
你得重新考量一下店里的摆设
you might want to rethink some of this artwork.
比如这个女人像条狗一样被链子拴住
I mean, this woman's actually on a leash like a dog.
你又不知道图画的背景故事
Well, you don't know the backstory.
或许她整天乱蹦到沙发上  才被拴住
Maybe she kept jumping up on the couch.
我感觉自己好酷啊
I feel cool.
就像穿靴子的猫
Like Puss in Boots.
我小时候一直都梦想当个咻噹侠盗
I always wanted to be a swashbuckler when I was a kid.
其实"咻噹"这词是两个字的组合
Technically, "swashbuckler" is a combination of two terms.
"咻"指的是挥剑的声音
"Swash" referring to the sound of the sword.
咻
Swash.
而"噹"
And then "buckler"
原意是指一个小手盾  可是你没有
meaning a small shield, which you don't have.
那我们还是能当咻咻侠盗啊
We can still be swashers.
说得好  靴猫剑客[孬种]
Well said, Puss.
先生们  欢迎来到击剑俱乐部
Gentlemen, welcome to the fencing club.
在开始之前  我想警告你们
Before we start, I just want to warn you,
击剑可不是闹着玩
fencing isn't a joke.
我希望你们来上课不是因为觉得
I hope you're not here because you think it's going to be
这会像《星球大战》一样
like Star Wars.
我们不是为那个而来的
That's not why we're here.
我来是以为会像《权力的游戏》中那样
Yeah, I'm here because I think it's gonna be like Game of Thrones.
或许跟《公主新娘》也沾点边
And maybe a little Princess Bride.
我忘了还有《公主新娘》
Ooh, ooh! I forgot about Princess Bride!
这才是我来的主因
That's my answer!
那很抱歉你们要失望了
Well, sorry to disappoint you,
击剑是很严肃的运动
but fencing is a serious sport.
如果你们不愿意全身心投入训练
If you're not willing to put in the effort,
那还是趁早离开吧
you might as well just leave now.
我们不怕做体力活动
We're not afraid of physical activity.
我今天已经"跑"了29公里了
I already ran 18 miles today.
好吧  那先从一些基本动作开始
All right. Let's begin with some fundamentals.
这是起势  预备姿势
This is the en garde position.
双脚成"L"形  脚跟在同一线上
Feet are in an "L." Heels in a straight line.
持剑手臂与躯干有一拳距离
Elbow is about a fist from the rib cage.
注意我的主导腿向前
Notice my dominant leg faces forward.
天啊
Oh, dear.
怎么了  库珀
What's wrong, Cooper?
我不太确定我的主导腿是哪条
Well, I'm not sure I have a dominant leg.
这两条腿都很听话不争宠
They're both pretty submissive.
你在公共厕所时
When you're in a public restroom,
习惯用哪只脚冲厕所
which foot do you flush the toilet with?
右腿  一直用右腿
Right. Always right.
他是右撇子
He's a righty.
好的  预备姿势
Okay, show me en garde.
很好  膝盖弯曲
Good. Knees bent,
略微超过脚尖
slightly over the toe.
非持剑的手臂抬起保持平衡
Non-sword hand up for balance.
我明天一定浑身酸疼
I am going to feel this tomorrow.
第一式叫向前移步
The first move is called an advance.
前脚往前迈一步  脚跟先着地
You move your front foot forward, heel to toe.
后脚跟上前
Back foot follows.
前脚往前迈  脚跟先着地
So front foot forward, heel to toe.
后脚跟上前
Back foot follows.
现在你们试试  向前
Now you try. Advance.
向前   向前
And advance. And advance.
这太简单了  根本不用穿护裆罩
This is easy. I didn't need to wear a cup.
很好
Good.
下一式叫向后移步
The next move is called a retreat.
后退
Step back.
后脚后移一步  前脚掌先着地
Back foot first, toe to heel.
前脚跟着后移
Front foot follows.
数到三
On three.
-我有个问题  -说
- Excuse me, Barry? - Yes.
我何时能用剑刺我的朋友
When can I stab one of my friends?
在击剑里  那个动作不叫"刺"
In fencing, we don't call it a stab.
-叫"击中"[触摸]  -我知道
- We call it a touch. - Uh, yes, I'm aware.
可如果我说我想"触摸"我的朋友
But if I say I want to touch one of my friends,
我会被人事部叫去训话
I'll get called into Human Resources.
好的  数到三
Okay, on three,
库珀和库萨帕里向前  其余两人向后
Cooper and Koothrappali advance, the other two retreat.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
非常好  动作互换
Very good. Switch it up.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
再换  一  二  三
Switch again. One, two, three.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我晚点打回去好吗
Can I call you back?
不  我在教课呢
No, I'm teaching a class.
当然  当然
Sure. Sure.
最多一小时吧
An hour, tops.
对  好的
Yeah. Okay.
好的
Okay. Yeah.
好  多谢
Okay. Thanks.
一  二  三
And one, two, three.
你有想过直接面向女性做宣传吗
Have you thought about advertising directly to females?
好吧
Hmm, okay.
也行
Well... All right.
这主意怎么样  在橱窗竖一块牌子写着
What if I put up a sign in the window that said,
"女人们  进来吧
"Women, come in.
别害怕"
Don't be afraid."
你看过网上对这地方的评价吗
Uh, have you read the online reviews for this place?
互联网阴暗负面
Eh, the Internet's so negative.
我尽量不看呢
I try to avoid it.
好吧  希瑟一号说
All right, well, Heather H. Says,
"店主全程都盯着我看
"The owner stared at me the whole time
眼睛都不眨一下"
and didn't blink once."
凯丽二号说
Kelly M. Says,
"开这家店的怪胎想约我
"The creepy guy who runs it asked me out,
我还没来得及拒绝  他就说自己蠢"
then called himself stupid before I could say no."
杰西卡三号说
Jessica K. Says,
"我跟变态店主说我喜欢他的衣服
"I told the weird owner that I liked his shirt.
结果他立马脱下给我"
He took it off and gave it to me."
瞧  太负面了
See? Negative.
伸出花剑
With your foil extended,
前腿前踢
kick your front leg up
后腿反推身体向前
and push off with your back leg.
你们试试
Now you try.
再来
And again.
瞧瞧咱们  就像火箭女郎
Look at us! We're like the Rockettes!
预备  莱纳德
En garde, Leonard.
准备好接受我狂风暴雨般的攻击[触摸]
Prepare yourself for a rigorous touching.
我叫埃尼戈·蒙托亚
My name is Inigo Montoya.
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father.
准备受死吧
Prepare to die.
我叫埃尼戈·蒙托亚
My name is Inigo Montoya.
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father.
准备受死吧
Prepare to die.
我以为你要演穿靴子的猫呢
I thought you were Puss in Boots.
对哦  抱歉
Oh, yeah, right. Sorry.
我是穿靴子的猫
My name is Puss in Boots.
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father.
准备受死吧
Prepare to die.
我还等着他教咱们用手套扇脸呢
I'm looking forward to him teaching us glove-slapping.
什么
What?
就是当我的尊严被侵犯时
You know, when my honor is insulted,
我需要跟某人决斗
and I need to challenge someone to a duel
挑衅的方式就是  甩手套扇那人的脸
by slapping them across the face with my glove.
你的尊严什么时候被侵犯了
When was your honor insulted?
上次做体检的时候
My last physical.
再说一次  医生并没有侵犯你的尊严
Again, that doctor didn't insult your honor.
他只是检查你的前列腺
Just checked your prostate.
我名叫小孤女安妮
My name is Little Orphan Annie.
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father.
准备受死吧
Prepare to die.
我是黑武士达斯·维达
My name is Darth Vader.
我就是你的父亲
I am your father.
准备受死吧
Prepare to die.
-真好玩  -很好
- This is fun. - Good.
能让你暂时忘记了艾米也不错啊
It's nice to see your mind off Amy.
艾米怎么了
What's going on with Amy?
虽然不管你的事
Not that it's any of your business,
她跟我分手了
but she broke up with me.
真的吗
Really?
很高兴知道
Good to know.
"很高兴知道"
"Good to know"?
他这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
他言下之意好像对艾米有意思
I hate to say it, but it sounds like he's interested in her.
这绝对无法接受
Well, that's unacceptable.
老兄  我知道你不高兴
Oh, buddy, I get that you don't like it,
但这事真由不得你
but it's not really up to you.
我知道  但他多蠢啊  瞧他那张蠢脸
Yeah, but he's dumb, and his face is dumb.
就算不是跟他
Look, even if it's not him,
艾米以后也可能跟其他人约会
Amy's probably going to date someone at some point.
你真的这么想吗
You really think so?
当然  她值得拥有幸福
Of course. She deserves to be happy.
你好大的狗胆
How dare you!
听着  我得警告你
Listen, I should warn you
约艾米可不是个好主意
that maybe asking Amy out isn't a good idea.
巴里  借一步说话
Barry, a word?
你将听到我刚说的话的疯狂升级版
And now the crazy version of what I just said.
如果你想追求艾米
If you intend to pursue Amy,
我别无选择  只能予以阻止
you leave me with no choice but to put a stop to it.
你要如何阻止我呢
And how are you gonna do that?
我要和你决斗
By challenging you to a duel.
你才上了一节课  我轻松就能废掉你
You've had one lesson. I'll destroy you.
所以这场决斗将定于
That is why the duel will take place
三年后的今天  正午时分
at high noon, three years from today.
如果你是一个货真价实的教练
If you're worth your salt as an instructor,
三年之后我应该准备好了
I should be ready by then.
还有你给我小心了
Yeah, and be warned.
我将击中[触摸]你全身各处
I'm going to touch you all over.
这席发言比我想的还要疯狂
That-that was crazier than I thought.
好了  虽然不一定是真的
All right, I'm not saying it's true,
但我们可以假设
but let's-let's consider for a moment
-问题是出在我身上  -就是
- that possibly I'm the problem. -Yeah.
-是的  -你可以这么说
- You are. - You can say it.
好吧  那么...
Okay, fine. What...?
我该怎么办呢
I mean, what can I do?
我一遇到女人就紧张
I get so nervous around women.
你现在跟我们说话
Well, you're talking to us now.
怎么看起来不紧张啊
I mean, you don't seem nervous.
那是因为我用了个小诀窍
Well, that's 'cause I'm doing that trick
就是想象你的听众都赤身裸体
where you imagine the audience is naked.
顺便一提  身材不错哦  妹子们
By the way, thumbs up, ladies.
你没听见自己刚才的话有多恶心人吗
Do you not hear how creepy that sounds?
我开玩笑而已
It was a joke.
是吗
Was it?
不  我还在继续想象呢
No, I'm still doing it.
好吧
Okay.
我无意冒犯你  不过
Don't be offended, but...
你这人到底有什么毛病啊
what went wrong with you?
可能我原以为我到这个年纪
I-I guess I assumed at this point in my life,
早就结婚  或者恋爱了
I would be married or in a relationship,
哪怕有只宠物
or even have a pet
不会跑掉或自杀的那种也好
that didn't run away or kill itself.
这事真的发生了吗
That really happened?
我不是特别肯定
I mean, I can't say for sure,
不过我发誓那兔子跳到车头之前
but I swear that rabbit looked me right in the eye
转身看了我一眼
before it hopped in front of that car.
总之  我单身越久
Anyway, the longer I'm alone,
就越饥不择食
the more desperate I get.
斯图尔特  我能理解你
Stuart, believe it or not, I understand.
在我遇见谢尔顿之前
You know, before I met Sheldon,
我曾经孤单了很长很长时间
I was alone for a really long time.
我竭尽一切让周围的人喜欢我
I was so desperate for people to like me,
当我遇见她们时
when I met these guys,
我用尽全力来隐藏我的不安全感
it took everything in my power to hide my insecurity.
好了  我想大家都感受到了
Okay, we're all feeling it.
好啦  我愿意和你约会
Yes, I'll go out with you.
我瞬间理解了那兔子的感受
Suddenly, the rabbit thing makes sense.
谢尔顿  想不到你居然想来运动酒吧
I'm surprised you wanted to go to a sports bar, Sheldon.
看看这些水泡
Look at this blister.
不管你怎么想  我们现在是运动健儿了
Like it or not, we're athletes now.
再说了  酒吧才是适合我的所在
Besides, a bar is where I belong.
我遇到了妞的问题
I'm having female problems.
如果你暴脾气又容易水肿  我知道原因[月经]
If you're cranky and retaining water, I have a theory.
谢尔顿  与其想着艾米和其他人约会
Sheldon, instead of focusing on Amy dating other guys,
也许你应该试着约一下其他女孩
maybe you should start thinking about dating another girl.
你疯了吗
That's ridiculous.
为什么
Why?
你以前还觉得自己永远不会和人交往
You never thought you'd end up in a relationship,
结果你遇到了艾米
and then you met Amy.
也许世界上还有其他适合你的人呢
Maybe there's someone else out there for you.
是的  可是佩妮结婚了  博纳黛特也结婚了
True, but Penny's married, and so is Bernadette.
而你女友的红发白皮肤
And your girlfriend has red hair and white skin,
会激起我的小丑恐惧症
which really rubs up against my clown phobia.
也许你应该考虑一下
Maybe you should consider women
除了死党的伴侣之外的
who aren't in serious relationships
其他女性
with your closest friends?
有一个前列腺医师  可我还生着她的气呢
There's that prostate doctor, but I'm still mad at her.
那有个女的
Oh, there's a woman.
我要让她当我女友
Oh, I'll make her my girlfriend.
在酒吧里追求陌生女人  通常会失败
Walking up to a strange woman in a bar usually doesn't work.
你忘了一件事
You're forgetting something.
姑娘们都爱运动员
Ladies love jocks.
他是喝了几口壮了怂人胆的啤酒
How many sips of that beer did he have?
-三口  -天啊
- Three. - Oh, boy.
打扰一下  我现在处于分手恢复期
Excuse me. I'm recovering from a recent breakup,
有人跟我说  跟另一个女人约会
and I'm told asking out another woman
也许会好受一些
might make me feel better.
如小智对皮卡丘所说的
And as Ash Ketchum said to Pikachu,
"就决定是你了"
"I choose you."
什么
What?
《口袋妖怪》的哏
It's a Pokemon reference.
我不知道那是什么意思
I don't know what that means.
对的时间遇见错的人
Well, we gave it a shot.
那你呢
How about you?
我结婚了  都当外婆了
I'm married, and I'm her grandmother.
错的时间遇见对的人
Ah, what might have been.
而你  代我向你马戏团的朋友们问好[红发白肤]
And you, give my regards to Barnum and Bailey.
斯图尔特简直像被拒绝专业户
Stuart took that rejection like a pro.
毕竟摄乳镜头拍得到他  不能暴怒
Well, he knew he was on the breast cam.
我没有过太多拒绝男人的经历
I don't have much experience turning men down.
不是很有意思
It wasn't so much fun.
你习惯就好了
Oh, you get used to it.
有的男人  你得一而再再而三地拒绝他
Some guys you have to turn down over and over.
或有时我们就嫁给他了事
And sometimes we marry them anyway.
奇了怪了
Well, this is weird.
-怎么了  -巴里·克瑞普吉约我出去
- What? - Barry Kripke just asked me out.
瞧你真行啊  一日两鸟
Look at you-- two guys in one day!
我就说修眉能改运吧
I told you things would change if you plucked your eyebrows!
他怎么说
What did he say?
"你好吗
"Hi, how are you? I was wondering
哪天下班以后一起去喝杯东西好吗"
if you'd like to get a drink after work sometime."
你要怎么做
Well, what are you gonna do?
不知道
I don't know.
我之前有想过以后肯定会跟别人约会
I guess I assumed that I would eventually date other people,
只是我没想到会这么快
but this is happening so fast.
能有什么损失吗
What can it hurt?
我希望下个约会对象
Well, I was hoping the next person I dated
能少像谢尔顿一点
would be a little less like Sheldon.
你是说不要科学家吗
You mean, not a scientist?
她说的应该是不要怪胎
I think she means not a weirdo.
你对他有好感吗
Are you attracted to him?
不知道
I don't know.
那你想象一下他裸体的样子  什么感觉
All right, well, what happens if you imagine him naked?
用不着想象
Oh, I don't have to imagine it.
我身上的味道好奇怪
I smell funny.
尝起来咸咸的
I taste salty.
你就是运动出了点汗
You're just sweaty from exercise.
还蛮美味的
And kind of delicious.
好奇要舔多少下才能舔到我的中心[棒棒糖]
I wonder how many licks it would take to get to the center of me.
医生的一根金手指  就能破"门"而入
I know it only takes one doctor's finger.
你好
Hello.
我们走  你们慢谈
We should let you guys talk.
对
Yeah.
你们不用离开
You don't have to leave.
瞧我飞速飘走
Look at me go!
伯纳黛特  你还要开车送我呢
Uh, Bernadette, you're my ride.
自己走路
Walk!
你最近好吗
How have you been?
最近还行
I'm doing all right.
我今天练击剑了
I tried fencing today.
顺利吗
How'd that go?
挺简单的
It was pretty easy.
应该是我"数学竞技"的背景有所助益
And I think my background in "mathletics" helped.
巴里·克瑞普吉也在
Barry Kripke was there.
我应该告诉你
I should let you know
他对你感兴趣想约你出去
that he expressed interest in asking you out.
其实他已经约了
Well, actually, he-he already did.
好吧
Okay.
但别陷太深
But don't get too attached to him.
再过2年又364天  他就死翘翘了
In two years, 364 days, he's a dead man.
我拒绝了
I said no.
有意思
Interesting.
我今天约了两个女人  都拒绝我了
I asked two women out today, and they both said no.
我不知道你想跟人约会呢
I didn't know you were interested in dating.
听说这有助于走出失恋阴霾
I've been told it's a good way to move on.
这样啊
Okay.
总之  很高兴再见到你
Anyway, um, it's nice to see you.
你看起来不错
You look good.
谢谢
Mmm, thanks.
我尝起来还很美味哦
And I taste good too.
华仔
Howie?
怎么了
What's up?
你的运动手环怎么显示昨天你跑了280公里
Why does your Fitbit say you ran 174 miles yesterday?